appnitro.com 2019-04-07

# Privacy Policy | HTML Form Builder Online, PHP Form Creator - MachForm

**Effective Starting: May 25, 2018  
Last Updated: May 15, 2018**

At Appnitro Software and our affiliated companies we are committed to respecting and protecting your online privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how Appnitro Software and its affiliates (“Appnitro Software,” “we,” “our” or “us”) collect, use, and share information in connection with your use of our websites (including www.machform.com), services, and applications (collectively, the “Services”).

## 1\. Information We Collect

#### **1.1 Information You Provide**

**1.1.1 Account and Profile Information.**  We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, or make purchases through the Services. We may ask for your contact information, including items such as name, company name, address, email address.

**1.1.2 Payment Information.**  When you add your financial account information to your account and purchase our services, that information is directed to our third-party payment processor ([FastSpring, LLC](https://fastspring.com/)). We do not store your financial account information on our systems (we do not know users’ credit card numbers); however, we have access to, and may retain, subscriber information through our third-party payment processor.

**1.1.3 Communications.**  If you contact us directly through email or when you open a support ticket on our site, we may receive additional information about you such as your name, email address, phone number, the contents of the message and/or attachments you may send us, and any other information you may choose to provide.

#### **1.2 Information We Collect When You Use Our Services**

**1.2.1 Form Data.**  We store your form data (questions and responses) for you, specifically when you’re using MachForm Cloud service. We don’t store any of your form data when you’re using MachForm Self-Hosted, nor we have any access to it.

**1.2.2 Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.**  As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, landing page, and referring URL.

**1.2.3  Your Use of The Services.** When you use our Services, specifically MachForm Cloud, we may collect information about your utilization of our Services, such as processor and memory usage, storage capacity and system-level metrics. We use this data to operate the Services, maintain and improve the performance and utilization of the Services, protect the security and safety of our Services and our customers, and provide customer support. We do not collect this information when you’re using MachForm Self-Hosted.

## 2\. How We Use Information We Collect

How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use and any preferences you have communicated to us. Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you.

**2.1 Form Data.** Your form data is owned by you and considered as private information. We may access your form data only when you provide written permission to us, to resolve technical issues.

**2.2 Personally Identifiable Information.**  We may use your personally identifiable information for any of the following purposes:

  * to respond to your inquiries and provide you with service and support
  * to analyze site usage and to improve the MachForm website and service
  * to track your use of our services
  * to notify you of changes to our website, to our agreements, or our products and services
  * to contact you about your account
  * to offer you new products and services that we believe may interest you
  * to allow us to suspend or terminate your account, if necessary

**2.3 For Research and Development.**  We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure, integrated, and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Services.

**2.4 For Customer Support.**  We use your information to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyze crash information, and to repair and improve the Services.

**2.5 For Compliance Purpose.**  We may use your information for compliance purposes, including enforcing our Terms of Service, or other legal rights, or as may be required by applicable laws and regulations or requested by any judicial process or governmental agency.

## 3\. How We Share Information We Collect

We may share the information we collect in various ways, including the following:

**3.1 Vendors and Service Providers.** We work with third-party service providers to render our Services, including (but not limited to) website and application development, cloud hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, payment processing, analysis, security. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under close instruction from us, including policies and procedures designed to protect your information. Complete list of our vendors is available within our Data Processing Agreement document.

**3.2 Business Transfer.**  Information may be disclosed and otherwise transferred to any potential acquirer, successor, or assignee as part of any proposed merger, acquisition, sale of assets, or similar transaction, or in the event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which information is transferred to one or more third parties as one of our business assets.

**3.3  As Required By Law and Similar Disclosures**. We may also share information to (i) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request; (ii) enforce this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof; (iii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; (iv) respond to your requests; or (v) protect our rights, property or safety, our users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and spam/malware prevention.

**3.4 With Your Consent.**  We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so.  For example, we often display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our public websites. With your consent, we may post your name alongside the testimonial.

## 4. Security

**4.1 Security Practices.** We take steps to protect the security of the personally identifiable information we collect, including, for example, physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards.

Although we take appropriate measures to ensure the security of your personal data, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot give absolute assurances that personally identifiable information we collect may not be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

For more information, please see our [MachForm Security](https://www.machform.com/infrastructure-security/) page.

**4.2 Data Locations.** MachForm Cloud servers are based in the United States.

## 5\. Data Retention

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information or the type of the service you’re using, as described in further detail below. After such time, we will delete your information from all of our servers, including backups.

**5.1 Account information.** We retain your account information for as long as your account is active and a reasonable period thereafter in case you decide to re-activate the Services.  We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations, and to continue to develop and improve our Services.

**5.2 MachForm Cloud.** We retain all your form data for as long as your account is active. When you terminate or cancelled your cloud subscription, all your form data will be automatically deleted within 30 days.

**5.4 MachForm Self-Hosted**. All your form data is stored in your own MySQL database server. We don’t have any access to your data, thus you’ll need to manage your own data retention policy.

## 6\. Your Data Protection Rights Under The GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic A, you have the following data protection rights:

  * If you wish to  **access, correct, update, or request deletion**  of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us. Your request may be limited in certain cases: for example, if fulfilling your request would reveal information about another person, or if you ask to delete information which we or your administrator are permitted by law or have compelling legitimate interests to keep.
  * You can  **object to the processing**  of your personal information, ask us to  **restrict the processing**  of your personal information, or  **request portability**  of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us.
  * You have the right to  **opt-out of marketing communications**  we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in the marketing emails we send you or from your account settings page.
  * Similarly, if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time.  Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

## 7\. Data Transfers

Personal information that you submit through the Services may be transferred to countries other than where you live, such as, for example, to our servers in the U.S.  Your personal information may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information.

We rely upon a number of means to transfer personal information which is subject to the European General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) in accordance with Chapter V of the GDPR. These include:

  * **Standard data protection clauses.**  We may, in accordance with Article 46 of the GDPR, transfer personal information to recipients that have entered into the European Commission approved contract for the transfer of personal data outside the European Economic Area.
  * **Other means**. We may, in accordance with Articles 45 and 46 of the GDPR, transfer personal information to recipients that are in a country the European Commission or a European data protection supervisory authority has confirmed, by decision, offers an adequate level of data protection, pursuant to an approved certification mechanism or code of conduct, together with binding enforcement commitments from the recipient to apply the appropriate safeguards, including as regards data subjects’ rights, or to processors which have committed to comply with binding corporate rules.

You can find out more information about these transfer mechanisms [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu_en).

## 8. Changes to Our Policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Services homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate your account(s), as outlined above.

## 9\. Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [customer.service@appnitro.com](mailto:customer.ser%76ic%65%40appnitro.co%6D)

The data controller of your personal information is Appnitro Software.
